Register of the Tom Killion papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1868-1997 (Boxes 6-20)
  - Horn of Africa, 1868-1997
    - Articles, Ethiopia
      - "'Tigrean Nationalism,' British Involvement and Haile Selassie's Emerging Absolutism: Northern Ethiopia, 1941-1943," [Erlich, Haggai, Asian and African Studies], 1981 (Box-folder 8: 26)
      - "Trends in the Ethiopian Economy,", 1970 (Box-folder 8: 27)
      - Working Papers on Society and History in Imperial Ethiopia: The Southern Periphery from the 1880s to 1974 [Donham, D. L.], 1980 (Box-folder 8: 28)
    - Articles, Horn of Africa
      - "Ethiopian and Eritrean Refugees in the United States" [Woldemikael, Tekle. M.], 1995 (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - Refugees and repatriation, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 9: 2)
      - Somalia, undated (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - "Upheaval in the Horn: Somalia, Eritrea, Ethiopia" [Middle East Research and Information Project], 1977 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Assistance - "Mutual Assistance Networks: The Case of Wolayita" [Alaro, Altaye], 1991 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Association
      - Editorial Association of Eritrean Culture and History, 1994 (Box-folder 9: 6)
      - Eritrea Material Aid Campaign (EMAC), 1981 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      - Eritrea: Various flyers, 1989 (Box-folder 9: 8)
      - Ethiopia: "The Social and Cultural Foundation of Gurage Associations" [Gadamu, Fecadu], 1970 (Box-folder 9: 9)
      - "Wage Pooling as a Form of Voluntary Association in Ethiopian and Other African Towns" [Comhaire, Jean], undated (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - Book review
      - "Eritrea: Historiography and Mythology" [Gilkes, Patrick, African Affairs], 1991 (Box-folder 9: 11)
      - "Eritrea Through Corrective Lenses" [Iyob, Ruth, Africa Today], 1990 (Box-folder 9: 12)
      - "Reassessing Ethiopia's Claim to Uniqueness" [Iyob, Ruth, Africa Today], 1989 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - Capital - "The Ethiopian Railway and British Finance Capital, 1896-1902" [Bekle, Shiferaw, Africa], 1980 (Box-folder 9: 14)
    - Conflict resolution - "The Horn of Africa: Prospects for the Resolution of Conflict" [Pateman, Roy, Northeast African Studies], 1990 (Box-folder 9: 15)
    - Demobilization - "Démobilisation et reconstruction en Érythrée" [Marchai, Roland], 1991 (Box-folder 9: 16)
    - Development, Ethiopia
      - Agriculture and industry, 1969 (Box-folder 9: 17)
      - "Évolution de la situation juridique du Chemin de fer de Djibouti à Addis Abeba de 1896 à 1977" [Pasteau, Michel], 1980 (Box-folder 9: 18)
      - "The Developing Industrial Relations System in Ethiopia" [Stutz, Robert], 1967 (Box-folder 9: 19)
    - Development, Sudan
      - "Capitalist Agriculture in the Sudan’s Dura Prairies," [Shepherd, Andrew, Development and Change], 1983 (Box-folder 9: 20)
      - "Developing the Traditional Sector in the Sudan," [Adams, Martin, and Howell, John, Economic Development and Cultural Change], 1979 (Box-folder 9: 21)
      - "Restructuring the Future Sudan,", 1980 (Box-folder 9: 22)
      - The Economic and Political Development of the Sudan [Lees, Francis, and Brooks, Hugh], 1977 (Box-folder 10: 1)
      - Growth and Adjustment in National Agricultures: Four Case Studies and an Overview [O'Hagan, J. P.], 1978 (Box-folder 10: 2)
      - "The Sudan: Musharaka,", 1987 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - Dispute - "Eritrea-Yemen Dispute Over the Hanish Islands" [Dzurek, Daniel J.], 1996 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Documents
      - Eritrea: Italian colonial documents, 1900s (Box-folder 10: 5)
      - "Documenting Ethiopia" [Prouty, Chris], 1991 (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Economy, Eritrea
      - Eritrean economy (1950-1954), 1993 (Box-folder 10: 7)
      - Statistics of industrial productions for the period 1964-1965, undated (Box-folder 10: 8)
      - "Wages and Compensation of Port Workers,", 1959 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - Economy, Ethiopia
      - "A Dura Revolution and Frontier Agriculture in Northwest Ethiopia, 1898-1920" [McCann, James C., The Journal of African History], 1990 (Box-folder 10: 10)
      - Imports and exports from Ethiopia, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 11)
      - "Moral Crusaders and Incipient Capitalists: Mechanized Agriculture and Its Critics in Ethiopia" [Rahmato, Dessalegn], 1986 (Box-folder 10: 12)
      - "Private Foreign Investment in Ethiopia (1950-1968)" [Mohammed, Duri, Journal of Ethiopian Studies], 1969 (Box-folder 10: 13)
      - Tables from the Ethiopian economy, 1970 (Box-folder 10: 14)
    - Education
      - "La scuola in Eritrea ieri e oggi" [Puglisi, Giuseppe, Africa], 1953 (Box-folder 10: 15)
      - "Rural Primary Education in Eritrea,", 1996 (Box-folder 10: 16)
      - "A Sociolinguistic Survey of Language Use and Attitudes Towards Language in Ethiopia: Implications for Language Policy in Education" [Teferra, Tsehaye], 1977 (Box-folder 10: 17)
    - Election, Ethiopia - "Puzzling Precincts, Illicit Elections, and Kebele Cabals,", 1992 (Box-folder 10: 18)
    - Famine, Ethiopia
      - "Managing Famine Disaster Popular Participation in Tigray," second draft, 1995 (Box-folder 10: 19)
      - Rural Vulnerability to Famine in Ethiopia, 1958-1977 [Wolde-Mariam, Mesfin], 1986 (Box-folder 10: 20)
    - Governance
      - Eritrean referendum, 1993 (Box-folder 10: 21)
      - Ethiopia: "Democracy, Local Governance, and Development in a Tigray Village,", 1996 (Box-folder 10: 22)
      - The government of Ethiopia, 1948 (Box-folder 10: 23)
        Includes "The Economic Background, Production and Trade Before 1935," focusing on Ethiopia.
      - Horn of Africa: Italians under the Eritrean-Ethiopian Federation, 1961, 1994 (Box-folder 10: 24)
    - Hearings, Ethiopia - "Senate Hearings on Ethiopia, Statement by John Hathaway Spencer,", 1976 (Box-folder 10: 25)
    - Historiography, Horn of Africa - Bibliography, 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - History, Eritrea
      - "Black Snake, White Snake: Bahta Hagos and His Revolt against Italian Overrule in Eritrea, 1894" [Caulk, Richard], 1986 (Box-folder 11: 2)
      - History, typed notes, undated (Box-folder 11: 3)
      - A History of Kagnew Station and American Forces in Eritrea [Rasmuson, John R.], 1973 (Box-folder 11: 4)
      - "Recovering Eritrea’s Neglected History,", 1994 (Box-folder 11: 5)
      - "The Land Tenure System in the Eritrean Highlands According to European Colonial Sources" [Taddia, Irma], 1984 (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - History, Ethiopia
      - "Axum,", undated (Box-folder 11: 7)
      - "Aksumite Chronology: Some Reconsiderations" [Munro-Hay, S. C.], 1989 (Box-folder 11: 8)
      - "Bad Men of the Borders: Shum and Shifta in Northern Ethiopia in the Nineteenth Century" [Caulk, R. A., International Journal of African Historical Studies], 1984 (Box-folder 11: 9)
      - "Banditry and Resistance: Noble and Peasant in Nineteenth Century Ethiopia" [Crummey, Donald, in Banditry, Rebellion and Social Protest in Africa], 1986 (Box-folder 11: 10)
      - A Chronicle of Emperor Yohannes IV (1872-1889) [Tafla, Bairu], 1977 (Box-folder 11: 11)
      - "Ethiopia and Garrison Government in the Ogadeen, 1887- c. 1930" [Garretson, Peter P.], undated (Box-folder 11: 12)
      - Ethiopia at Bay: A Personal Account of the Haile Selassie Years [Spencer, John H.], 1983 (Box-folder 11: 13)
      - "French Colonial Ambitions over Ethiopia,", 1983 (Box-folder 11: 14)
      - "History of Eclipses and Comets in Ethiopia" [Pankhurst, Richard], undated (Box-folder 11: 15)
      - "Introduction to the Taxation System of the Rising Absolutist State of Ethiopia, 1855-1868" [Tsegaye, Tegenu], 1991 (Box-folder 11: 16)
      - "Preservation of Historical Monuments in Ethiopia" [Woredekal, Solomon], 1989 (Box-folder 11: 17)
      - "Quest for the Sea: Ras Tafari in Europe, 1924" [Marcus, Harold G.], 1984 (Box-folder 11: 18)
      - "Social Mobility and Dissident Elites in Northern Ethiopia: The Role of Bandits, 1900-1969" [Fernyhough, Timothy, in Banditry, Rebellion and Protest in Africa], 1986 (Box-folder 11: 19)
      - The Nile Tributaries of Abyssinia and the Sword Hunters of the Hamran Arabs [Baker, Samuel W.], 1868 (Box-folder 11: 20)
      - "The State in Zamana Masafent (1786-1853): An Essay in Reinterpretation" [Bekele, Shiferaw, in Kasa and Kasa: Papers on the Lives, Times and Images of Téwodros II and Yohannes IV], 1990 (Box-folder 11: 21)
      - "The Takarir of Gallabat" [al-Naqar, Umar], 1984 (Box-folder 11: 22)
      - "Un artisan lyonnais d’influence française en Éthiopie,", 1950s (Box-folder 12: 1)
      - "Une tentative d’interprétation de l'administration coloniale fasciste en Éthiopie, 1936-1941,", 1991 (Box-folder 12: 2)
      - "Why a Greek? An East African Frontier in 1905" [Trench, Charles Chenevix, History Today], 1965 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - Identity - "In Search of an Identity: Amhara/Tegrean Relations in the Late Nineteenth Century" [Taddia, Irma], 1991 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - Industry, Eritrea
      - "Aziende Agricole,", 1947 (Box-folder 12: 5)
      - Deluxe Shoe Factory, 1993 (Box-folder 12: 6)
      - "Industrie italiane in Eritrea" [De Leone, Enrico, Africa], 1949 (Box-folder 12: 7)
      - "Le opera pubbliche in Eritrea,", 1936 (Box-folder 12: 8)
      - "Le pagine d'un libro contabile" [Puglisi, Giueppe, Africa], 1950 (Box-folder 12: 9)
      - Mining and oil, 1995 (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Industry, Ethiopia
      - Directory of Manufacturing Industry in Ethiopia [Imperial Ethiopian Government Ministry of Commerce, Industry and Tourism], 1969 (Box-folder 12: 11)
      - "Ethiopia’s Coffee Problems" [ Ethiopia Observer], 1958 (Box-folder 12: 12)
      - "Ethiopia’s Industrial Progress" [ Ethiopia Observer], 1957 (Box-folder 12: 13)
      - "Gross Value of Production in Manufacturing Industries," typed report, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 14)
      - "Role of Small Scale Enterprise in Africa with Particular Reference to Ethiopia" [Sethi, Meera], 1984 (Box-folder 12: 15)
      - "Summary of Manufacturing Industries," typed report, 1957 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - International relations - "Ethio-French Relations, 1917-1937" [Alaro, Altaye], 1990 (Box-folder 12: 17)
    - Interviews, Eritrea
      - Interview transcripts of Woldeab Woldemariam and the labor movement, part one, 1983 (Box-folder 12: 18)
      - Interview transcripts of Woldeab Woldemarim, part two, 1983 (Box-folder 12: 19)
      - Interview with comrade Al Amin Mohammed Said, 1981 (Box-folder 12: 20)
    - Investment - "New Decree Provides for the Encouragement of Capital Investment in Ethiopia,", 1969 (Box-folder 12: 21)
    - Keynote addresses
      - H. E. Isaias Afewerki, President of the State of Eritrea, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 12: 22)
      - Ethiopia, speech delivered by Comrade Mengistu Hailemariam on the occasion of the 50th anniversary Victory Day, 1991 (Box-folder 12: 23)
    - Labor, Eritrea
      - Collective agreement between S.I.A. Cotton Farm P.L.C. and Cotton Farm Labor Union, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 12: 24)
      - Conflict between management and workers at the salt production, 1994 (Box-folder 12: 25)
      - Conflitto di tribu a Zeban Seda, 1950 (Box-folder 12: 26)
      - Constitution of National Confederation of Eritrean Workers (NCEW) (with English translation), 1994 (Box-folder 12: 27)
      - Employment Act, The Eritrean Gazette, 1958 (Box-folder 12: 28)
      - "Employment Act, 1958" [ Eritrea Today], 1959 (Box-folder 12: 29)
      - "Eritrean Employment Act of 1958: Its Present Status" [Means, Robert C., Journal of Ethiopian Law], 1968 (Box-folder 12: 30)
      - Eritrean workers, Massawa, 1941 (Box-folder 12: 31)
      - Eritrean Workers’ Struggle: A History, printed booklet (with handwritten English translation), 1981 (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - "Important Days in the History of Eritrean Workers,", 1986 (Box-folder 13: 2)
      - "Labor Policy for a Market-Driven Economy" [Habte-Giorgis, Berhe], 1992 (Box-folder 13: 3)
      - Labor Proclamation No. 125, 1952 (Box-folder 13: 4)
      - Organizational chart of the National Confederation of Eritrean Workers, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 5)
      - "Per la storia del sindacalismo in Eritrea,", 1975 (Box-folder 13: 6)
      - Programme of the 4th Congress and Founding Congress of the NCEW, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 7)
      - Project proposal for workshops and confederation Congress on the reconstruction and reorganization of the National Union of Eritrean Workers (NUEW), 1994 (Box-folder 13: 8)
      - Questionnaire, workers’ organization, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 9)
      - Voice of the Workers, newsletter, 1994 (Box-folder 13: 10)
      - "Worker Strikes in the Port Administration of Massawa at Various Times,", 1994 (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - Labor, Ethiopia
      - "Collecting Bargaining on Terms, Issues and Conditions of Employment in Nine Selected Agreements,", 1960s (Box-folder 13: 12)
      - "Confederation of Ethiopian Labor Unions,", 1981 (Box-folder 13: 13)
      - "Confederation of Labor Unions,", 1965 (Box-folder 13: 14)
      - Confederation of Ethiopian Labor Unions (CELU), "Sulla questione dei diritti dell’umo e dei diritti deomcratici (sessione del 21 Settembre),", 1976 (Box-folder 13: 15)
      - Court decision, HVA Sugar Corporation vs. HVA Sugar Workers Union, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 16)
      - Decree No. 49 of 1962 ["The Labour Relations Proclamation, 1962"] (Box-folder 13: 17)
      - Diabaco Cotton Company, 1960 (Box-folder 13: 18)
      - "Documents on the History of the Labor Movement in Ethiopia," translated by Awetu and Tom Killion, 1982 (Box-folder 13: 19)
      - Dues payment book, Wonji, HVA, 1964 (Box-folder 13: 20)
      - "Employees Who May Not Strike" [Means, Robert C., Journal of Ethiopian Law], 1967 (Box-folder 13: 21)
      - "Ethiopian Labour Relations: Attitudes, Practice and Law" [Morehous, Lynn G., Journal of Ethiopian Law], 1970 (Box-folder 13: 22)
      - Extract of selected speeches of his Imperial Majesty Haile Selassie I, 1962 (Box-folder 13: 23)
      - Haile Selassie I University Extension, "Labor Economics and Public Administration," an intensive course to be held in Asmara, 1963 (Box-folder 13: 24)
      - "The History and Growth of Labor Unions in Ethiopia" [Mekuria, Kiflu], 1973 (Box-folder 13: 25)
      - IFPAAW representative to SLF (SIDA and CELU) on mission to Ethiopia, 1972 (Box-folder 13: 26)
      - "Industrial Conflict and Labor Politics in Ethiopia: A Study of the March 1974 General Strike" [Sisaye, Seleshi, Plural Societies], 1977 (Box-folder 13: 27)
      - Interview notes, DD Cotton Factory, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 28)
      - "An Introduction to Labour Developments in Ethiopia" [von Baudissin, Georg Graf, Journal of Ethiopian Law], 1965 (Box-folder 13: 29)
      - "Italian and 'Native' Labor During the Italian Fascist Colonial Occupation of Ethiopia, 1935-1941" [Pankhurst, Richard, Ghana Social Sciences Journal], 1972 (Box-folder 13: 30)
      - "Labor, Law and Practice in the Empire of Ethiopia" [United States Department of Labor], 1966 (Box-folder 13: 31)
      - Labor legislation, 1970 (Box-folder 13: 32)
      - "Labour-Management Relations" [ International Labour Review], 1963 (Box-folder 13: 33)
      - "Land, Labor, and Coffee: The South’s Role in Ethiopian Self-Reliance, 1889-1935" [McClellan, Charles W., African Economic History], 1980 (Box-folder 13: 34)
      - Manpower Strategy for Developing Countries: Lessons from Ethiopia [Ginzberg, Eli and Smith, Herbert A.], utilization for CELU article, 1967 (Box-folder 14: 1)
      - Minutes of railroad workers’ strike dispute, 1957 (Box-folder 14: 2)
      - Name of the union around Addis Ababa and within the city, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 3)
      - "New Ethiopian Legislation on Employment,", 1963 (Box-folder 14: 4)
      - "The Confederation of Ethiopian Labour Unions" [ The Manager and Entrepreneur], 1969 (Box-folder 14: 5)
      - "The Confederation of Ethiopian Labour Unions: A Decade of Organized Development,", 1973 (Box-folder 14: 6)
      - "The Development of Some Institutions Concerned with Labour Relations in Ethiopia" [Gebregziabher, Seyoum], 1969 (Box-folder 14: 7)
      - "The Emerging Trade Unionism in Ethiopia" [Zack, Arnold M., Journal of the Society of Public Administration], 1964 (Box-folder 14: 8)
      - "The New Labor Relations in Ethiopia" [Zack, Arnold M.], 1964 (Box-folder 14: 9)
      - The Provisional Military Government of Socialist Ethiopia, the Labor Proclamations of 1975 (Box-folder 14: 10)
      - "Le syndicat des cheminots Franco-Éthiopien,", circa 1960 (Box-folder 14: 11)
      - "The Tri-Partite Institutions (Government, Employers and Unions)," the labor sector, 1969 (Box-folder 14: 12)
      - The Workers Voice, 10th anniversary of the founding of the Confederation of Ethiopian Labour Unions (CELU), 1972 (Box-folder 14: 13)
      - Petition to His Imperial Majesty Haile Selassie I, hand delivered, 1967 (Box-folder 14: 14)
      - Petition to the Ministry of Interior, Public Security Office by Wonji Sugar Factory workers, 1961 (Box-folder 14: 15)
      - "Petition of Wonji Workers to the Emperor,", 1967 (Box-folder 14: 16)
      - Population and labor, 1964 (Box-folder 14: 17)
      - Programme for fraternal delegates to the 7th ordinary general conference of the CELU, 1970 (Box-folder 14: 18)
      - Railroad workers (CFE) constitution, 1955 (Box-folder 14: 19)
      - "Railroad Workers and History of the Labor Movement in Ethiopia,", 1980s (Box-folder 14: 20)
      - Report on workers’ education in Ethiopia, 1964 (Box-folder 14: 21)
      - "Resolution Passed by the Extra-Ordinary Congress of CELU Held September 18-21, 1975," unofficial translation from the original Amharic (Box-folder 14: 22)
      - "Self-Help in Ethiopia" [Pankhurst, Dr. Richard, and Eshete, Endreas, Ethiopian Observer], 1958 (Box-folder 14: 23)
      - "Trade Unionism Awakens in Ethiopia" [Zack, Arnold M.], 1964 (Box-folder 14: 24)
      - "Trade Unionism Develops in Ethiopia" [Zack, Arnold M.], 1964 (Box-folder 14: 25)
      - "La trasformazione della Confederation in Ethiopian Labour Unions nel processo revoluzionario Etiopico,", 1976 (Box-folder 14: 26)
      - "Voice of Labour,", 1970 (Box-folder 14: 27)
      - "Wages and Salaries Paid" [ Ministry of Commerce and Industry Bulletin], 1957-1958 (Box-folder 14: 28)
      - Wages in the Cotton Company of Ethiopia, 1960s (Box-folder 14: 29)
      - "Wonji Sugar Plantation Arbitration Decision,", circa 1960 (Box-folder 14: 30)
      - Wonji sugar workers’ self-help association’s constitution, 1960 (Box-folder 14: 31)
      - Wonji work conditions and exploitation, 1960s (Box-folder 14: 32)
      - Wonji workers’ constitution, 1962 (Box-folder 14: 33)
    - Labor, Sudan
      - "The Political Economy of Capitalist Agriculture in the Central Rainlands of Sudan" [O'Brien, Jay, Labour, Capital and Society], 1983 (Box-folder 14: 34)
      - "Wage Labourers in the Fragmented Labour Market of the Gezira, Sudan" [Abdelkarim, Abbas, Africa: Journal of the International African Institute], 1986 (Box-folder 14: 35)
    - Language, Eritrea
      - Tigrinya language, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - Tigrinya names, 1931 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Law, Ethiopia
      - Civil code, 1960 (Box-folder 15: 3)
      - Labor Law Handbook, 1972 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Literature - "Modern Ethiopian Literature: The Creation of Ethiopic Printers' Type" [ New Times and Ethiopia News], 1955 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Management - "Strategic Integration of Macro-Policy and Human Resources Management in Eritrea,", 1996 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - Manufacturing - Manufacturing industry, Ethiopia, 1957 (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - Multinational corporations - "Notes on Multinational Corporations in Ethiopia" [Bondestam, Lars, The African Review], 1975 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Nationalism, Eritrea
      - "Discourses on Eritrean Nationalism and Identity" [Sorenson, John, The Journal of Modern African Studies], 1991 (Box-folder 15: 9)
      - "Eritrea: Some Further Comments on an African Colonial State" [Taddia, Irma], 1992 (Box-folder 15: 10)
      - "Nationalist Independence in the New World Order,", 1994 (Box-folder 15: 11)
      - Notes and citations from 1964, 1994 (Box-folder 15: 12)
      - "The Post-war Transition,", 1996 (Box-folder 15: 13)
      - "Reactive and Pro-Active Nationalism in Eritrea, 1961-1991,", undated (Box-folder 15: 14)
      - "The Role of Asmara Students in the Eritrean Nationalist Movement: 1958-1968" [Ammar, Wolde-Yesus, Eritrean Studies Review], 1996 (Box-folder 15: 15)
      - "Unità nazionale e nazionalismo eritreo, difficoltàe contraddizioni di una lotta di liberazione,", 1977 (Box-folder 15: 16)
    - Nationalism, Horn of Africa
      - "The National Question in Eritrea and Ethiopia,", 1991 (Box-folder 15: 17)
      - "Regional Hegemony: Domination and Resistance in the Horn of Africa" [Iyob, Ruth, The Journal of Modern African Studies], 1993 (Box-folder 15: 18)
    - Nationalism, Sudan - Islam, Nationalism and Communism in Traditional Society: The Case of Sudan [Warburg, Gabriel], 1978 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - Nationalities, Eritrea
      - Afar, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 15: 20)
      - Eritrea, 1945, 1954 (Box-folder 15: 21)
        Includes clippings from A History of the Beja Tribes of the Sudan by A. Paul and Notes on Beni Amer Society by S. F. Nadel.
      - "L’actualité du problème Afar,", 1994 (Box-folder 15: 22)
      - The Blin of Bogos [Ghaber, Michael], chapters 3-5, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 23)
    - Nationalities, Somalia - "Factors of Intermediacy in Nineteenth-Century Africa: The Case of the Issa of the Horn" [Coats, Peter D.], 1982 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Organization, Ethiopia - "Rules and Regulations of the Wonji Club,", 1969 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Peace - "Prospects for Peace and Stability in the Horn of Africa," 5th Northeast African Studies conference, 1989 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Politics, Eritrea
      - "Eritrea: A Revolution in Process" [Connell, Dan, Monthly Review], 1993 (Box-folder 16: 4)
      - "Birth, Development and Crises of the Muslim League in Eritrea" [Marchal, Roland], 1989 (Box-folder 16: 5)
      - "Dalla federazione all’annessione la lotta del popolo eritreo per la sua indipendenza,", 1975 (Box-folder 16: 6)
      - "The Eritrean Autonomy 1952-1962: Its Failure and Its Contribution to Further Escalation" [Erlich, Haggai, Models of Autonomy], 1981 (Box-folder 16: 7)
      - "Eritrean Independence: The Legacy of the Derg and the Politics of Reconstruction" [Pool, David, African Affairs], 1993 (Box-folder 16: 8)
      - Eritrean People’s Liberation Front (EPLF), press releases, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 16: 9)
      - General information and facts, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 16: 10)
      - "Irredentism Redux: Some Thoughts on Anti-Eritrea Lobby in the United States,", circa 1990 (Box-folder 16: 11)
      - "Problemi politici e costituzionali dell’Eritrea di ieri e di domani,", 1975 (Box-folder 16: 12)
      - "Eritrea: The End of the Beginning" [Styan, David, L'Afrique politique], 1994 (Box-folder 16: 13)
      - "The Eritrean Unionist Party and Its Strategies of Irredentism, 1941-50" [Tekeste, Negash], 1991 (Box-folder 16: 14)
      - Eritrea: The Guerrillas of The Red Sea [Peninou, Jean Louis], 1975 (Box-folder 16: 15)
      - The Struggle over Eritrea, 1962-1978: War and Revolution in the Horn of Africa [Erlich, Haggai], Section I and II, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 16)
      - United States consular reports, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 16: 17-19)
      - United States consular reports, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
      - United States documents on Eritrea, 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - Politics, Ethiopia
      - Coalition of Ethiopian Democratic Forces (COEDF), 1991 (Box-folder 17: 4)
      - Ethiopia in 1990: The Revolution Unraveling [Henze, Paul B.], 1991 (Box-folder 17: 5)
      - "The Ethiopian Land Reform: From Political Change to Economic Development" [Ottaway, Marina], 1980s (Box-folder 17: 6)